survivalfrog.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Survival Frog

**Effective Date: October 26, 2018**

To review material modifications and their effective dates scroll to the bottom of the page.

Survival Frog, LLC ("Survival Frog") owns and operates this SurvivalFrog.com website business. All references to "we", "us", this "website" or this "site" shall be construed to mean Survival Frog. We understand that visitors to this website are concerned about the privacy of information. The following describes our privacy policy regarding information, including Personal Information (defined below), that we collect through this website. 

By using this website you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

How We Modify This Privacy Policy 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, and without prior notice, by posting an amended Privacy Policy that is always accessible by clicking on the "Privacy Policy" link on this site's home page. Your continued use of this site indicates your acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy.

You should check the Privacy Policy through this link periodically for modifications by clicking on the link provided near the top of the Privacy Policy for a listing of material modifications and their effective dates.

The Types of Information We Collect And How We Collect It

Personal Information. We collect personal information that may be used to identify you (“Personal Information”). We collect Personal Information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or order an affiliate product from another company we are working with. Personal Information that we collect may vary with each separate purpose for which you provide it, and it may include one or more of the following categories: name, physical address, an email address, phone number, credit card information including credit card number, expiration date, and billing address.

Usage Data. We reserve the right to collect information based on your usage of this site which is information collected automatically from this site (or third party services employed in this site ), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the users who use this site, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the user, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the site) and the details about the path followed within the site with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, heat map data, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the user's IT environment ("Usage Data"). Usage Data is essentially anonymous when collected, but could be used indirectly to identify a person.

How We Use Your Information

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

To personalize your experience   
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)

To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)

To improve customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)

To process transactions  
(We may share or sell information with third parties for marketing or other purposes without your consent)

To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature

To send periodic emails

The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order or request, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, promotions, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

We reserve the right to make full use of Usage Data without restriction. For example, we may use Usage Data to compile and analyze statistics and trends about the use of this site, and otherwise administer and improve this site for your use.

How We Disclose Or Share Your Information; Your California Privacy Rights

Personal Information. We may share or sell Personal Information to third parties for marketing or other purposes without your consent. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding disclosure of their Personal Information to third parties for purposes of direct marketing. You may request further information about our compliance with California Civil Code Section 1798.83 at the following email address: support(at)SurvivalFrog.com. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per registrant each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this the address provided above.

Disclosure to Affiliated Entities. We reserve the right to provide your Personal Information to any affiliated entities we may have, including our subsidiaries. Affiliated entities are entities that we legally control (by voting rights) or that control us.

Disclosure to Service Providers for Website Operations. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information to our trusted service providers that assist us with the operation and maintenance of this site. For example, we may use third parties to process payments, host our servers, provide security, and provide production, fulfillment, optimization, analytics, and reporting services. We will take commercially reasonable efforts to cause these third parties to agree to hold your information in confidence or to disclose information only to third parties that we believe in good faith have instituted and follow privacy and security policies that are acceptable to us.

Disclosure to Successors. If we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, or if we sell this website business or a line of business from this website, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information to protect our rights or as required by law.

Disclosure Incident to Legal Process and Enforcement. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary (i) to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request (such as for example, to comply with a subpoena or court order), or (ii) to investigate or enforce violations of our rights or the security of this site.

When We Participate In a Joint Venture. We may participate with another company or individual for purposes of jointly promoting our products, services, promotions or contests or their products, services, promotions, or contests. We reserve the right to right to disclose your Personal Information to them for purposes of (i) compensation, transaction processing, fulfillment, and support, and (ii) for purposes of offering you other products, services, promotions, and contests. These joint venture marketing partners may also contact you regarding other products, services, promotions, or contests.

Marketing Partners.  We may share your Usage Data with our marketing partners including third party service providers, advertisers, advertising networks and platforms, advertising agencies, and data brokers and aggregators to serve and offer personalized ads.  We may share Personal Information with our marketing partners to correlate and match our list with our marketing partners' lists for purposes of creating an "audience" for serving personalized ads.

How We Protect Your Information

We will implement reasonable and appropriate security procedures consistent with prevailing industry standards to protect data from unauthorized access by physical and electronic intrusion

We utilize password protected directories and databases to safeguard your information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your Personal Information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

Despite all of these efforts to protect your information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot, therefore, warrant or ensure the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk..

Specific Information About Cookies, Web Beacons, And Behavioral Ads

1st Party Cookies. We use 1st party cookies (passed by us) to keep track of your current shopping session to personalize your experience and so that you may retrieve your shopping cart at any time.

3rd Party Cookies for Web Analytics and Reporting. We reserve the right to use web analytics services provided by 3rd parties. These services use 3rd party cookies (cookies passed by others, not by us) to collect Usage Data about your use of this site. These web analytics services may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on the service's behalf.

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google utilizes the data collected to track and examine the use of this site, to prepare reports on its activities, and to share them with other Google services. Information collected: cookie and Usage Data. Visit Privacy Policy at https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/?fg=1 You may optout of the Google Analytics service with the Google's Browser Add-on that's available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/

3rd Party Cookies for Crediting Purchases To Affiliates; Flash Cookies. We reserve the right to use 3rd party cookies, including Flash cookies, for purposes of crediting any purchase you may make on this site to one of our affiliate marketing partners that may have referred you to us. These cookies will only be used for purposes of crediting sales to the referring affiliate and not for other purposes such as serving behavioral ads. Flash cookies are not the same as “browser cookies”. Flash cookies consist of an Adobe Flash Media Player local shared object (LSO) that is used for tracking purposes. The Adobe Flash Media Player is software that enables users to view content on their computers. Flash cookies are also accompanied by a browser cookie. If you delete the browser cookie, the Flash cookie may automatically create (or re-spawn) a replacement for the browser cookie. However, recent announcements indicate that IE 8 and IE 9 browsers have been updated to also delete Flash cookies with an their “delete browsing history” feature. For more information, Google “How to delete flash cookie”.

Web Beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs or clear gifs - are used to assist in delivering cookies, and they allow us to count users who have visited pages of our site. We may include Web Beacons in promotional e-mail messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. **Re-Marketing, Targeted Ads, Online Behavioral Ads**

We reserve the right to participate with third party advertising partners in remarketing and behavioral targeting programs. These services allow us and our partners to display ads that are likely to be more relevant (such as behavioral or targeted ads that are based on information about your browsing history). This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using cookies to transfer information to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

These third party ad servers or ad networks may also use cookies and other tracking devices to track your activities on this site to measure advertisement effectiveness and other reasons that will be provided in their own privacy policies. Tracking may include, but not limited to, the following: first party cookies, third party cookies, anonymous cookies, persistent identifiers, email optin, and search engine keywords. We have no access or control over these cookies and other tracking devices that may be used by third party advertisers, and we have no responsibility or liability for the policies and practices of these sites.

AdWords Remarketing (Google) - We reserve the right to participate in AdWords Remarketing which is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this site with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick cookie. Information collected: cookie and Usage Data. For the opt-out, visit https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en 

For information in general about Google's remarketing ad campaigns, and specifically about information regarding DoubleClick cookies and how to control and manage Google's advertising cookies for these campaigns, visit http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/

For another Google resource for opting our of Google's use of cookies, visit http://www.google.com/settings/ads 

For information regarding how Google uses data when you use Google's partners' sites or apps, visit http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ 

For anther resource recommended by Google for opting out of a third party vendor's use of cookies, visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google) - We reserve the right to participate in any and all of the following Google Analytics Advertising Features provided by Google Inc. -   Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. These features use first party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) for connecting the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the DoubleClick cookie (a third party cookie). Information collected: cookie and Usage Data, including audience data such as age, gender, and interests. For the opt-out, visit https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en You may optout of the Google Analytics service with the Google's Browser Add-on that's available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/

For information in general about Google's remarketing ad campaigns, and specifically about information regarding DoubleClick cookies and how to control and manage Google's advertising cookies for these campaigns, visit http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/

For another Google resource for opting our of Google's use of cookies, visit http://www.google.com/settings/ads 

For information regarding how Google uses data when you use Google's partners' sites or apps, visit http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ 

For anther resource recommended by Google for opting out of a third party vendor's use of cookies, visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

Custom Audience (Facebook). We may participate in Facebook.com's Custom Audience program which enables us to display personalized ads to persons on our email lists when they visit Facebook.com.  We provide Personal Information such as your email address and phone number to Facebook to enable Facebook to determine if you are a registered account holder with Facebook. You may optout of participation in our Facebook Custom Audience by sending an email, from the email address you are opting out of, to the email address provided in our contact information below. For your optout to be effective, you must: (i) place the following text in the subject line of the email - "Opting Out of Facebook.com Website Custom Audience Ads", and (ii) in the body of the email, include your name and email address. We will forward your name and email address to Facebook.com with a request to delete you from all of our Facebook Custom Audience Ads.

Other Remarketing Services. We reserve the right to participate in additional remarketing services that will be similar to the remarketing services described above. These services will allow us and our partners to display ads that are likely to be more relevant (such as behavioral or targeted ads that are based on information about your browsing history). You may access these services to opt out: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ and http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ .

**Social Media Interactions**

We invite you to socialize and share your participation with this site and purchases. If you choose to use social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, and Instagram, you will be allowing interaction with these platforms or other external platforms directly from this site, and in the process you may be sharing certain profile elements, including your comments. This sharing is subject to each social media program's privacy policies.

**Do Not Track Requests**

Some Web browsers incorporate a "Do Not Track" feature that signals to websites that you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. Each browser communicates "Do Not Track" signals to websites differently, making it unworkable to honor each and every request correctly. In order to alleviate any communication error between browsers and website, we do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals at this time. As the technology and communication between browser and website improves, we will reevaluate the ability to honor "Do Not Track" signals and may make changes to our policy.

Updating Personal Information

Upon request, we will permit you to request or make changes or updates to your Personal Information for legitimate purposes. We request identification prior to approving such requests. We reserve the right to decline any requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require unreasonable time or effort of our technical or administrative personnel, or undermine the privacy rights of others. We reserve the right to permit you to access your Personal Information in any account you establish with this site for purposes of making your own changes or updates, and in such case, instructions for making such changes or updates will be provided where necessary. 

Onward Transfer Outside Your Country Of Residence

Any Personal Information which we may collect on this site will be stored and processed in our servers located only in the United States. By using this site, if you reside outside the United States, you consent to the transfer of Personal Information outside your country of residence to the United States.

Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are committed to preserving online privacy for all of its website visitors, including children. This site is a general audience site. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we will not knowingly collect any information from, or sell to, children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian who has discovered that your child under the age of 13 has submitted his or her personally identifiable information without your permission or consent, we will remove the information from our active list, at your request. To request the removal of your child's information, please contact our site as provided below under "Contact Us", and be sure to include in your message the same login information that your child submitted.

Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information found at this link: <http://survivalfrog.com/pages/about-us>

2488 W 2nd Ave.  
Denver, CO 80223  
USA

support@SurvivalFrog.com  
(800) 773-7737

Material Modifications Effective February 4, 2016:

  * Re-classified “Non-Personal Information” as “Usage Data”.

  * Added a sharing option for joint venture partners.

  * Updated disclosures for Re-Marketing, Targeted Ads, Online Behavioral Ads.

  * Added do-not-track request notice.
